Brotherhood of Locomotive Engineers Records 5147
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Brotherhood of Locomotive Engineers Records
1907-1969
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Brotherhood of Locomotive Engineers (BLE)
5147
3 cubic feet
3 linear ft.
Records (documents).
Files of the Brotherhood of Locomotive Engineers.
5604321
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, February 21, 2014
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 07, 2019
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Locomotive engineers -- United States.; Locomotive engineers -- Labor unions -- United States.; Brotherhood of Locomotive Engineers (U.S.)
5604321
- US Court of Appeals, Brief of Brotherhood of Locomotive Engineers as Amicus Curae (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Outline Statement by the National Rules Committee of the Brotherhood, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Brotherhood of the Locomotive Engineers, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Scope and Contents
  July 16 1963
- Engineers 30% Wage Case, Earnings of Railroad Engineers, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Engineers' 30% Wage Case, 1953-1954 Wage Movement (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Engineers' 30% Wage Case, Earnings of Railroad Engineers, 1st Supplement, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Engineers' 30% Wage Case, Wage Differentials, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Engineers' 30% Wage Case, Pattern Settlements in the Railroad Industry 1937-1953, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Engineers' 30% Wage Case, Differentials, Wage Rates and Earnings, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Engineers' 30% Wage Case, History of the Diesel Rules Movement Prior to the Second and Third Diesel Cases, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Engineers' 30% Wage Case, Differentials, Wage Rates and Earnings, 2nd Supplement, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Engineers' 30% Wage Case, Differentials, Wage Rates and Earnings 1st Supplement, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Engineers' 30% Wage Case, Excerpts from Report of the Eight-Hour Commission, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Engineers' 30% Wage Case, The Rates and Bases of Pay and Working Conditions of Engineers and Firemen 1907-1953, 1941-1953 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Volume 2
- Engineers' 30% Wage Case, The Rates and Bases of Pay and Working Conditions of Engineers and Firemen (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Volume 1
- Engineers' 30% Wage Case, Statement Showing Certain Details of the Working Conditions and Arbitrary Payments Enjoyed by Engineers, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Engineers' 30% Wage Case, Documents, Letters and Data Pertaining to the Diesel Agreement, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Engineers' 30% Wage Case, Documents and Letters Pertaining to Supplement No. 15 to General Order No. 27, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Engineers' 30% Wage Case, The Rates and Basis of Pay and Working Conditions of Engineers and Firemen, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Engineers' 30% Wage Case, Earnings Data, Engineers' Extra Boards, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Engineers' 30% Wage Case, Job Preference Studies, Supplement, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Engineers' 30% Wage Case, Job Preference Studies, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Engineers' 30% Wage Case, Age Groups of Locomotive Engineers, Earnings of Locomotive Engineers 65 Years and Over, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Engineers' 30% Wage Case, Engineers' Jobs, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Engineers' 30% Wage Case, Material Relating to Promotions Terminal Railroad Association of ST. Louis, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Engineers' 30% Wage Case, Material Relating to Promotions St. Louis Southwestern Railway Lines, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Engineers' 30% Wage Case, Louisville and Nashville Railroad Miscellaneous Data, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Engineers' 30% Wage Case, Louisville and Nashville railroad Firemen's Seniority Rosters, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Engineers' 30% Wage Case, Louisville and Nashville Engineers' Seniority Rosters, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Engineers' 30% Wage Case, Chicago, Milwaukee, St. Paul and Pacific Railroad Company, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Engineers' 30% Wage Case, The Railroad Financial Situation, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Engineers' 30% Wage Case, Long Term Trends Railroad and Other Industries, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Engineers' 30% Wage Case, Train Studies, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Engineers' 30% Wage Case, Supplemental Material Relating to the Current Wage Movement, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Engineers' 30% Wage Case, Louisville and Nashville Railroad Economic and Financial Data, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Engineers' 30% Wage Case, Pennsylvania Railroad, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Engineers' 30% Wage Case, Statement of William White Before Emergency Board 106, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  February 19 1954
- Engineers' 30% Wage Case, Supplement to Carriers' Exhibit No. 36 the Railroad Financial Situation, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- National Railroad Adjustment Board BLE and Various Railroad Companies, 1962-1965 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- BLE, 1952-1969 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- BLE National Railroad Adjustment Board Parties to Dispute Awards, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Washington Jobs Protection agreement Dispute Involving BLE-BLF&E, ORL and BRT vs. D&RGW, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Modernization of the Wage-Rule Structure of Railway Operating Employees, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  April 3 1963
- Vocation Disputes General Correspondence, 1944-1948 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Vocation Decisions and Agreements, ORC, SUNA, BRJ, BLE, BLE&F, 1942-1948 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- SBA No. 390 to Dispose of Deadlocked August 11 1948 Cases, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- August 11 Decisions, Other Organizations, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  January 17 1963
- Decisions August 11 1948 Agreement, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  December 1960
- August 11 1948 Rules Agreement Decisions Rendered, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  January 24 1966
- Rules Agreement August 11 1948 Disputes Committee, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  May 4 1966
- BLE, BLF&E Agreement, Cleveland Union Terminal (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Dispute BLE, Oklahoma Railroad, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Report of the Board of Arbitration, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  November 2 1912
- Minority Report of FA Burgess and Timothy Shea, 1959-1960 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- BLE Awards, Strikes, Arbitration Part 1, 1948-1958 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- BLE Awards, Strikes, Arbitration Part 2, 1947-1966 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- BLFE vs. Certain Carriers, etc. Volume 2, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Transportation Brotherhoods and Atchison, Topeka and Tanta Fe Railway, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Decision of Committee BLF&E-42-W, 1961-1967 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Decision of Committee, Case No. W-F-155, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- McDaniel's File, NRAB Awards Dispute, 1930-1943 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Central of Georgia BLE, BLF&E, ORCB, BRT Arbitration Award, 1956-1966 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Decisions Memorandum Agreement 1949 Disputes Arising, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Cases on Questions Involving Application of Rules Agreement of August 11 1948, 1950-1955 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Decisions Under Memorandum Agreement of 1949, 1949-1953 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Decisions and Disputes Under Memorandum Agreement of 1949, 1949-1950 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- RLEA Decisions and Correspondence, 1939-1947 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Washington Jobs Protection Agreement, Railroads Becoming Parties, 1947-1956 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Washington Job Protection Agreement RLEA General Correspondence, 1940-1947 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Dispute BLE vs. Denver and Rio Grande Railroad Company, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- RLEA Washington Jobs Agreement, 1956-1958 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Joint Conference Committee Disputes Application of Agreement of 1936, 1949-1953 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- RLEA Dispute Information Agreement of 1936, 1947-1956 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- 1953 Wage Movement Wage Differentials, 1930-1953 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Brotherhood of Locomotive Engineers, 1874-1943 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Official Report of Agreements, 1907-1908 (Box 3, Folder 13)